Tinker Bell and the Great Fairy Rescue is a animation,
adventure, family film directed by Bradley Raymond.
During a summer stay on the mainland, Tinker Bell is accidentally
discovered while investigating a little girl's fairy house.
As the other fairies, led by the brash Vidia, launch a daring rescue in the middle of a
fierce storm, Tink develops a special bond with the lonely, little girl.
Tinker Bell (voice), played by Mae Whitman.
Lizzy Griffiths (voice), played by Lauren Mote.
Dr. Griffiths (voice), played by Michael Sheen.
Vidia (voice), played by Pamela Adlon.
Silvermist (voice), played by Lucy Liu.
Iridessa (voice), played by Raven-Symoné.
Tinker Bell and the Great Fairy Rescue is a 2010 American animated fantasy adventure film and the
third installment of the Disney Fairies franchise produced by Disneytoon Studios.
It revolves around Tinker Bell, a fairy character created by J.
Barrie for his 1904  play Peter Pan, or The Boy Who Wouldn't Grow Up, and featured
in subsequent adaptations, especially in Disney's animated works.
Animated by Prana Studios, the film was produced using digital 3D modeling.
It was released on DVD and Blu-ray by Walt Disney Studios
Home Entertainment on September 21, 2010.
Unlike the other films in the series, it takes
place entirely away from Pixie Hollow.
The film explores themes of rescue, london, england,
countryside, flying, parent child relationship.